# CHARLES DAVIS, JR.

828 Smithfield Drive, Apt 1107, Sagamore Hills OH | 216-798-8752 | csdj92@gmail.com

## Summary

Full Stack Software Engineer with desirable qualities as a new hire. As a self-starter, I enjoy diving into the world of code with a curiosity to learn, develop, create, and improve. Prioritizing my growth as a full stack engineer is essential. By nature, I am very teachable and always willing to listen and learn. All while maintaining the comfortability to research a topic and overcome difficult problems independently. As an employee, I am motivated, time conscious, and willing to learn new technologies.

## **Technical Skills**

| React.js | Redux.js | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | JSON | MS SQL | Ruby On Rails | Ruby | Git | Routes | Bootstrap | RESTful API | Sinatra |

# **Technical Projects**

### Real Estate

Features full Google and github login and user authentication. This project demonstrates proficiency in third-party login middleware, user login, user permissions and RESTful routes while using Ruby on Rails for validations. An additional feature includes functionality of password encryption using Ruby's bcrypt hashing encryptor, to bring a safe experience to businesses and their users.

- Backend Ruby on Rails, Database SQLite
- Front end engineered using JavaScript and Bootstrap
- URL: https://github.com/csdj92/real-estate-project

#### Local Events

Local events uses Ruby on Rails as an API and Javascript as the frontend. This project demonstrates proficiency in design and architect features across frontend and backend as well as creating a SPA.

- Integration of Javascript and Rails
- Use of ES6 & object orientation
- URL: https://github.com/csdj92/Local-event-finder-JS

#### Web Scraper

Web scraper is a CLI written in Ruby and is used to scrape an API. This project demonstrates the capacity to make a Ruby gem as well as how to access data received from an API, object orientation, and how to iterate through collections.

- Utilizes DRY as a principle to keep code clean
- Use of good object orientation
- URL: https://github.com/csdj92/Rick-and-Morty-CLI

#### Education

09/2020 - 02/2021 - **Flatiron School** - *New York, New York* 

Five-month online coding program designed to develop skills in dynamic web-based software systems using various programming languages.

09/2014 - 05/2017 - Cleveland State University - Cleveland, Ohio

Earned credits towards a degree in Health Sciences.

#### Work Experience

12/2019 - 09/2020 - Dialysis Technician at Centers for Dialysis Care - Beachwood, Ohio

06/2019 - 11/2019 - Package Handler at United Parcel Service - Laguna Beach, California

05/2016 - 03/2019 - Patient Care Nursing Assistant at Cleveland Clinic - Cleveland, Ohio